有一个非常强大的机制
There is an extremely powerful mechanism
在 CSS 中称为继承。
in CSS called inheritance.
所以现在让我们学习所有关于继承的知识。
And so let's now learn all about inheritance.
实际上，我们之前已经看到了继承的作用。
And actually we already saw inheritance in action before.
所以，记得回到本节的开头，
So, remember back at the beginning of the section,
我提到过，例如，这里的这个元素，
I mentioned that for example, this element here,
所以这个强元素的劳拉·琼斯，
so this Laura Jones, which is a strong element,
仍然获取段落元素的样式
still gets the styles of the paragraph element
它位于其中，对吗？
inside of which it is located, right?
所以让我们在这里检查这个元素。
So let's inspect this element here.
所以当然它是一个强大的元素，
And so of course it is a strong element,
所以作为默认样式，
and so as a default style,
所以这就是用户代理样式表还记得吗？
and so that's the user agent style sheet remember?
所以默认情况下，它的字体粗细是粗体，对吧？
So as a default, it gets the font weight of bold, right?
但是在这里我们看到它也被继承了
But then here we see that also it gets inherited
来自段落，因此来自其父元素。
from the paragraph, so from its parent element.
所以这里它得到斜体，字体大小的 18 像素
So here it gets the italic, the 18 pixels of a font size
以及 1.5 的行高。
and also the line height of 1.5.
所以基本上这意味着继承
And so basically what this means is that inheritance
是一种机制，通过它某些样式
is a mechanism by which some styles
所以有些属性会继承它们的值
so some properties get their values inherited
从父元素到子元素。
from parent elements to child elements.
所以现在让我们大范围地使用它
So let's now use this in a big way
通过在 body 元素上设置一些样式。
by setting some styles onto the body element.
所以，我们使用body元素来设置一些样式
So, we use the body elements to set some styles
因为body元素是父元素
because the body element is the parent element
我们的 HTML 文档中的所有其他元素。
of all the other elements in our HTML document.
因此，如果我们在主体中设置某些属性，
And so if we set certain properties in the body,
那么它们的值将被继承
then their values will get inherited
到他们所有的子元素。
to all of their child elements.
现在并不是所有的属性都被继承了
Now not all properties do actually get inherited
它主要是关于文本的。
it is mostly the ones that are about text.
所以让我们从一个非常简单的开始，
So let's start with a very simple one,
所以颜色，让我们将颜色设置为红色。
so the color, and let's set the color to red.
现在你认为在这种情况下会发生什么
Now what do you think is going to happen in this situation
假设我们实际设置了颜色
given that we actually set the color
大部分这些元素已经在这里了吗？
on most of these elements here already, down here?
走着瞧，
Well, let's see,
因此，当我们重新加载时，这里并没有真正改变。
and so, as we reload nothing really changed here.
原因是，虽然这种红色
00:02:29,130​​ --> 00:02:30,880
还是被继承了，
And the reason for that is that while this red color
is still got inherited,
这个有色属性就在这条规则中
this colored property right here in this rule
确实覆盖了继承的样式，好吗？
did override the inherited style, okay?
所以继承的样式很容易被覆盖
So the inherited styles are easily overwritten
每当有任何规则
whenever there is any rule
这适用于相同的财产。
that applies for the same property.
所以继承的属性很容易被覆盖
So an inherited property is very easily overwritten
根据任何规则，该规则具有相同属性的值。
by any rule, which has a value for that same property.
所以在某种意义上，我们可以说继承的价值观
So in a sense, we can say that inherited values
是那些优先级最低的。
are the ones who have the lowest priority.
但无论如何，如果我们现在从这里移除颜色
But anyway if we now removed the color from here
让我们把它注释掉，
and let's just comment it out,
然后，好吧，所有的文本
then, well, all the texts
没有声明颜色的将变为红色。
which does not have a color declared will become red.
所以，这里的这个，所有的，
So, this one here, all of this,
现在这个还是蓝色的
now this one is still blue
因为我们在这里覆盖它，对吧？
because we're overriding it here, right?
但是其他一切都是红色的。
But then everything else is red.
所以现在我们可以做的是设置文本颜色
And so now what we can do is to set the text color
我们实际上对这里的身体感兴趣。
that we're actually interested in here in the body.
所以现在所有的文字都是灰色的，就像以前一样，
And so now all the text is gray, such as before,
但我们所要做的就是在 body 中声明这个值，
but all we have to do is to declare that value in the body,
然后这个值 444 被继承为颜色
and then this value 444 gets inherited for the color
对于所有没有颜色声明的规则。
for all of the rules, which do not have a color declaration.
现在让我们对字体系列做同样的事情。
And now let's actually do the same with the font family.
所以我们实际上将它从这里剪切并粘贴到这里
So we'll actually cut it from here and paste it here
这个也一样。
the same for this one.
所以再一次，所有的元素
And so once again, all the elements
继承了这里的无衬线值
got the sans-serif value here inherited
对于字体家族财产，好吗？
for the font family property, all right?
实际上，如果我们回到这里一步，
And actually, if we go back here one step,
所以我只是把它放回去。
so I'm just putting it back.
所以你在这里看到它们实际上仍然存在的链接
So you see that here the links they're actually still
在衬线样式中，因为在我们的代码中没有，
in the serif style, because nowhere in our code,
我们为他们编辑无衬线字体系列，对吧？
we edit the font family of sans-serif to them, right?
所以现在我又在这里做，
So now I'm doing it again here,
把它贴在这里看看现在发生了什么？
pasting it here and take a look what happens now?
你现在看到它们就像
And you see now they are just like
无衬线文本的其余部分。
the rest of the text in sans-serif.
所以实际上我们在这里不再需要这个选择器，
And so actually we no longer need this selector here,
我们可以摆脱它。
we can just get rid of it.
可以肯定的是，
And just to be sure,
我真的想在这里再澄清一次。
I really want to clarify something here one more time.
所以这真的是元素继承值
So this is really elements inheriting values
对于彼此的某些属性。
for certain properties from one another.
所以这不是冲突的选择器
So this is not conflicting selectors
或者换句话说，这里的主体选择器
or in other words this body selector here
不是选择所有这些元素，好吗？
is not selecting all of these elements, okay?
它不适用于所有元素
It does not apply to all the elements
相反，我们所做的是声明值
instead, what we do is to declare values
对于这里的这些属性，
for these properties here,
例如颜色和字体系列。
such as color and font family.
然后他们只是被传下来
And then they simply get passed down
对所有子元素
to all the child elements
包含在体内的东西。
that are contained within the body.
这就是我们使用这项技术的原因
And so that's why we use the technique
将这些与文本相关的属性
of putting these properties that are related to text
和身体，好吗？
and to the body, okay?
因为这些是
Because these are the ones
然后我们希望页面上的所有元素都具有。
that we then want all of the elements on the page to have.
现在，正如我之前所说，
Now, as I said before,
许多风格实际上并没有得到继承，
many styles do actually not get inherited,
因为那将是非常不切实际的
because that would be very impractical
对于大多数属性。
for most of the properties.
例如，假设边框顶部，
For example, let's say border top,
所以如果我们声明一个 10 像素的边框顶部
so if we declare a border top of 10 pixels
和我们身体的蓝色相得益彰，
and solid with our blue color to the body,
让我们看看会发生什么。
let's see what happens then.
事实上，它只是简单地编辑了这个蓝色边框
And indeed it simply edit this blue border
到我们身体元素的顶部，
to the top of our body element,
但它并没有对所有子元素都这样做，对吧？
but it did not do so to all of the child elements, right?
因为再一次，那将是非常非常不切实际的。
Because again, that would be very, very impractical.
现在让我们快速浏览一下
And now let's take a quick look
在继承的图形表示
at a graphical representation of inheritance
真正让它一清二楚。
to really make it crystal clear.
所以这里我们有一个非常简单的网页示例，
So here we have a very simple example of a webpage,
它只包含一个导航、一个 H1 和一个 P 元素。
which simply contains a navigation, an H1, and a P element.
而在右边，
And on the right side,
我们也有一些body元素的样式
we also have some styles for the body element
特别是颜色、字体大小、字体系列、
and in particular, the color, font size, font family,
和边框顶部。
and border top.
现在当然是body元素
Now of course the body element here
是所有其他三个元素的父元素。
is the parent element of all these other three elements.
因此，多亏了继承
And so therefore, thanks to inheritance
所有这三个元素，基本上都可以访问
all of these three elements, basically get access
到这三个继承的属性。
to these three properties that are inherited.
再一次，所有这三个属性
And again, all these three properties
基本上与文字有关，
are basically related to text,
而另一方面，
while on the other hand,
边框属性不会被继承。
the border property does not get inherited.
所以并不是所有的属性都会被继承，
So not all of the properties do get inherited,
但它主要是与文本相关的。
but it is mostly the ones related to text.
他们有很多属性的大清单
And they have a big list of many of the properties
确实会被继承，
that do get inherited,
因此，如果您愿意，可以查看它们。
so you can take a look at them if you'd like.
但不管怎样，别说我们也有规矩
But anyway, let's not say that we also have a rule
对于 H1 元素。
for the H1 element.
所以它基本上声明了一种新颜色
And so it declares basically a new color
和新的字体大小。
and a new font size.
所以它更大，它是蓝色的。
So it's bigger and it is blue.
所以现在发生的是这两个声明
And so what happens now is that these two declarations
确实会覆盖继承的样式。
do actually overwrite the inherited styles.
因此对于H1，颜色不再是灰色
Therefore for the H1, the color is no longer gray
并且字体大小不再是 16 像素，
and the font size is no longer 16 pixels,
但它现在是蓝色和 32 像素。
but instead it is now blue and 32 pixels.
所以这是继承的视觉表现，
So this is a visual representation of inheritance in action,
我希望让它更清楚一点
which I hope makes it a little bit more clear
这样你才能真正理解它是如何工作的。
so that you can really understand how it works.
所以也许需要更多时间看看这个
So maybe take some more time looking at this
再多研究一下这个例子，
and studying this example a little bit more,
然后我们实际上会再得到一次
and then we will actually get one more time
回到我们的代码。
back to our code.
我现在想向你展示的是继承
And what I want to show you now is that inheritance
实际上也适用于更小的规模，
actually also works on a much smaller scale,
这也是我们一直在做的事情。
which is something that we also do all the time.
所以继承不仅有助于放置样式
So inheritance is not only helpful by putting styles
进入体内，也可以在其他情况下。
into the body, but also in other situations.
所以假设我们想要改变
So let's say that we wanted to change
这四个链接的大小在这里。
the size of these four links here.
这实际上很容易，
That would actually be very easy,
我们所要做的就是让我们去那里。
all we would have to do is to let's go there.
所以会给他们上课
So would be to put a class on them
然后根据班级选择这些链接，对吗？
and then select these links based on the class, right?
或者我们也可以做这样的事情，
Or we could also do something like this,
所以我们可以做 nav 然后选择
so we could do nav and then select
里面的八种元素
the eight elements in there
与伪类关闭链接，对吗？
with the pseudo class off link, right?
假设我们希望字体大小为 18 像素，
Let's say we wanted the font size to be 18 pixels,
所以你看到这确实有效。
and so you see that that actually worked.
但现在让我们说，
But now let's say that we,
出于某种原因，这里也有一段
for some reason also had a paragraph in here
说这是导航。
saying this is the navigation.
所以这现在可能是 22 像素大。
And so this is now probably 22 pixels big.
让我们看看，是的，因为这是默认设置
Let's see, yeah, because that's the default
我们为段落设置的，
that we set for the paragraphs,
但我们也希望这是 18 像素，
but we also want this to be 18 pixels,
就像我们导航中的所有内容一样。
just like everything here in our navigation.
那么，我们怎么能这样做呢？
So, how could we do that?
好吧，当然我们可以像这样在这里添加
Well, of course we could add that here like this
它会再次起作用，对吗？
and it would work again, right?
但我们也可以以更好的方式做到这一点。
But we could also do it in a much better way.
所以我们不需要所有这些，
So we don't need all of this,
我们需要做的就是说导航
all we need to do is to say nav
然后在这里设置字体大小为18像素，
and then set the font size to 18 pixels in here,
然后所有其余的都应该继承这些样式。
and then all of the rest should inherit those styles.
现在实际上这里的段落并没有继承它
Now actually the paragraph here does not inherit it
因为我们特意设置了字体大小为22
because we specifically set a font size of 22
已经为这些段落了。
for the paragraphs already.
所以这可能不是一个很好的例子，
So that might not be such a good example,
让我们在这里使用一个强元素。
let's use a strong element here.
好的，所以现在应该是 18 像素
Okay, and so now this should be 18 pixels
就像这里指定的那样。
just as specified here.
所以如果我们把它拿回来，那么让我们看看我们得到了什么。
So if we took this back, then let's see what we got there.
好吧，真的没什么，
All right, so nothing really,
但是现在如果这里打开了，
but now if this was here turned on,
因此，如果我们将导航中的字体大小设置为 18 像素，
so if we set the font size in the navigation to 18 pixels,
那么现在我们可以看到这里的强元素
then now we could see that the strong element here
从导航继承了18个像素，好吗？
got the 18 pixels inherited from nav, okay?
所以现在这里的一切都是 18 像素
And so now everything here is 18 pixels
这要归功于继承，好吗？
and that's thanks to inheritance, okay?
所以这是我们一直使用的技术，
So this is a technique that we use all the time,
但让我们不要真正摆脱这里的强者。
but let's not actually get rid of the strong here.
再说一次，我实际上可以注释掉这段代码
And again, I can actually comment out this code
就像我们之前在 CSS 中所做的一样
just like we did in CSS before
通过点击命令或控制斜线，好吗？
by hitting command or control slash, all right?
现在刚刚结束，
And now just to finish,
实际上还有另一种方式
there is actually another way
为所有元素添加一些样式。
of adding some styles to all of the elements.
所以让我们回到这里，我会把它放在这里。
So let's go back up here actually, and I will put it here.
我说的是通用选择器
And what I'm talking about is the universal selector
我在幻灯片中提到的关于冲突选择器的内容。
that I mentioned in the slide about conflicting selectors.
所以基本上是通用选择器
So basically the universal selector
只需选择页面上的每个元素。
simply select every single element on the page.
所以如果我们真的想要，这很有用
And so this is useful if we actually want
应用于所有元素的某个属性，
a certain property applied to all elements,
但它不会被继承。
but which does not get inherited.
例如，我们想要的所有元素的颜色，
So for example, the color we want on all the elements,
但是颜色会被继承，
but the color gets inherited,
所以我们可以简单地把它放在身体里，对吧？
and so we can simply put it here in the body, right?
但是，现在想象一下我们想要
However, now imagine that we wanted
所有元素的边框顶部，例如这个。
the border top on all the elements, so this for example.
我们可以将其粘贴在这里，然后重新加载
We could paste this here and as we reload
我们会得到这个美丽的结果。
we would get this beautiful result.
所以你看到每一个元素
So you see every single elements
这包括像这里的新兴市场和强者。
and that includes like the EM here and the strong.
所以他们现在都有这个边框顶部，对吧？
So all of them now have this border top, right?
所以不是很有帮助，但它有助于证明
So not really helpful, but it helps demonstrate
我们真的可以应用某种风格
that we really can apply a certain style
到页面上的每个元素。
to every single element on the page.
请记住，这个选择器
Just keep in mind that this selector
实际上是优先级最低的那个。
is actually the one with the lowest priority.
所以很容易简单地覆盖它，好吗？
So it would be very easy to simply overwrite this, okay?
假设我们的身体上有红色，
Let's say that here we had red on the body,
然后这个会是红色的
and then this one would be red
只有所有其他的都是蓝色的。
and only all the other ones would be blue.
再一次，因为这是一个元素选择器
And again, because this is an element selector
因此它比通用选择器具有更高的优先级。
and so it has a higher priority than the universal selector.
但是让我们把它放回去
But let's put it back
实际上让我们在这里关闭它。
and actually let's turn this one off right here.
所以通用选择器其实是相当重要的
So the universal selector is actually quite important
现在我们还没有一个大的用例，
for now we don't have a big use case for it yet,
但我们很快就会，然后我会再解释一下。
but we will soon and then I'll explain it a little bit more.
但现在，我想让你明白的
But for now, what I want you to understand
是不是有很大的不同
is that there is a big difference
通用选择器之间
between the universal selector
和身体选择器。
and the body selector.
所以通用选择器只适用
So the universal selector simply applies
对所有元素，
to all the elements,
并且不涉及继承。
and there is no inheritance involved.
因此，这是完美的
And therefore, this is perfect
如果你想申请某个属性，
if you want to apply a certain property,
不会自动继承的
that does not automatically get inherited
到所有元素。
to all the elements.
另一方面，
On the other hand,
我们在 body 中放置的任何样式都会被继承。
any style that we put here in the body gets inherited.
所以这只是一个完全不同的机制
And so that's simply a completely different mechanism
而不是使用通用选择器。
than using the universal selector.